# **Mary Mccannon**

Plainfield, IL - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Mary-Mccannon/6857b2f2efa16a24

Currently part-time, looking for another part-time position. Full-time for two and one-half years as accountant for a physician keeping track of insurance billing, patient's accounts, payroll, quarterly payroll reports, and generally keeping the Doctor up-to-date on his business. Two years as accountant for a local lawn care company. Fifteen years experience in Finance/Banking software. Ten years experience in Futures and Options operations. Seven years in software testing. Knowledgeable in banking products. Good verbal communication skills, problem solving.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

GINNY'S HALLMARK STORES - July 2012 to October 2014

Responsible for paying bills, keeping the accounts up-to-date. Work with Tax Accountant. Run monthly reports for the owners. Send them spread sheets three times a week showing current positions.

#### Accountant for Dr. Liske

FOXLAND RESPIRATORY CONSULTANTS - Sandwich, IL - September 2009 to August 2012

managing the billing to insurance companies, patient accounts, payroll for entire staff, quarterly payroll reports. I kept him up-to-speed on the financials of his company, going over budgets and expectations. Left because he quit his practice

TRIPLE TAKE LAWN CARE - Plainfield, IL - April 2007 to September 2008

I was the only accountant for 2 privately owned lawn care companies. Each had approximately 20 employees and a budget over 1 Million dollars. I was responsible for AP/AR, payroll, quarterly taxes, budgeting, credit card payments. I reported directly to the owners.

## **Senior Software Testing Analyst**

ABN AMRO - 2001 to 2006

Tested vendor as well as in-house software. Consulted with team of professionals to ensure software was delivered into production on time and within budget,

- As senior lead responsible for all phases of testing--test plan, schedule, budget, test scripts, execution of scripts, defects,
- Responsible for signoff on software to be implemented into production.
- Last two years working exclusively on vendor package (RTS) for multi-million dollar system to enhance REPO trading abilities for Wholesale and Retail traders.
- Developed Sybase queries for automated trade entry from Sybase database to RTS vendor package when no one else thought it could be done.

ABN AMRO - Chicago, IL - 1994 to 2006

ABN AMRO, a prominent international bank ranked13th in the world, with global focus on multinational corporations and financial institutions as well as private clients.

#### **Senior Business Analyst**

ABN AMRO - 1998 to 2001

Consulted with users for business requirements. Took business requirements to developers and assisted in designing software to meet those requirements

- Wrote business requirement specifications for vendors.
- Trained users on vendor package.
- Consulted with developers in designing database populated by flat files from vendor package then to generate files for on-line delivery to the general ledger and DDA systems.
- Member of a six-person team that delivered into production one vendor package for Money Market traders, multi-million dollar project.
- Tested new requirements developed by vendor.

ABN AMRO - 1997 to 2001

# Was able to give senior management

ABN AMRO - 1996 to 1997

Special Projects (1996 - 1997)

Reported directly to senior management on special projects.

- · Trained others in area on futures and options.
- Balanced a clearing account that had been out of balance for several years, using historical FX rates, determine errors in posting to account. Was able to give senior management a detail report going back seven years with errors and adjustment to bring this account into balance.

#### **Senior Operations Officer**

ABN AMRO - 1996 to 1996

Organized the first Futures and Options operations area at Chicago branch. Responsible for all aspects of operations, balanced with exchanges, booked to the general ledger, reported to senior management on profit and loss.

- Supported up to 25 traders on a daily basis.
- Well-respected for exchange knowledge of futures and options.
- When ABN AMRO purchased a local trading firm, I was the only person in the Chicago branch with knowledge for due diligence of new company.

## **Operations Officer**

CONTINENTAL BANK - Chicago, IL - 1987 to 1994

Chicago, Illinois 1987 - 1994

Chicago-area bank that specialized in full banking services to medium and large sized corporations nationwide.

#### **OPERATIONS**

**Operations Officer** 

Responsible for day-to-day operations in the futures and options department. Supported up to six traders, balanced with the exchanges, made daily entries to the general ledger and reported to senior management on profit and loss.

BANK OF AMERICA FUTURES INC - Chicago, IL - 1985 to 1987

Bank of America is one of the world's largest financial institutions, serving individual consumers, small and middle market businesses and large corporations with a full range of banking, investing, asset management and other financial and risk-management products and services. BAFI is a separate division responsible for a presents on all major trading markets in the world.

Operations

Began as input operations clerk, gathering trading information from both Board of Trade and Chicago Mercantile Exchange, responsible for out-trades, quarterly delivery of futures and options valued at more than \$1 million. Final responsibilities involved balancing with the exchanges and customers and working on the phone desk with customers at the Chicago Board of Trade in the 30 year bond pit.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **MBA**

Keller Graduate School 1984

## **MSW**

George Williams College 1975